export const GENERALKNOWLEDGEINARTSA2016 = [

{
id: "question1",
question:  "1. The ancient Greeks rubbed the unpainted parts of their houses with",
A: "wax.",
B: "kaolin.",
C: "slip.",
D: "grease",
answer: "D. Shapes, colours and textures",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question2",
question:  "2. A concentration of colour in an area is described as",
A: "chrome",
B: "tint.",
C: "value.",
D: "shade",
answer: "A. Black",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question3",
question:  "3. The major exponent of Cubism was",
A: "Cezanne.",
B: "van Gogh.",
C: "Picasso.",
D: "Gauguin.",
answer: "C. Hard-work and imagination.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question4",
question:  "4. What was the major driving force behind the Egyptian civilization?",
A: "Labour",
B: "Belief",
C: "Industrialization",
D: "Democracy",
answer: "C. Stone and bone.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question5",
question:  "5. The following comprises of secret societies of the Bambara except",
A: "Ntomo.",
B: "Komo.",
C: "Flankuru.",
D: "Poro.",
answer: "D. Focal area",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question6",
question:  "6. The space left at the end of a screen frame to hold printing paste is known as",
A: "registration mark.",
B: "lacquered space.",
C: "printing are",
D: "dye well.",
answer: "C. Rites of passage.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question7",
question:  "7. The original “Discus thrower” was made by",
A: "Myron.",
B: "Picasso.",
C: "Michelangelo.",
D: "Praxiteles.",
answer: "C. Corinthian style of architecture was invented",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question8",
question:  "8. In Africa, prehistoric art is found in",
A: "Morocco.",
B: "Guinea",
C: "Mali.",
D: "Gabon.",
answer: "A. Bark",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question9",
question:  "9. Asymmetry is more desirable than symmetry because it",
A: "brings a monotonous effect.",
B: "makes an equal balance.",
C: "creates variety in composition.",
D: "shows correct proportion.",
answer: "C. Oil colour.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question10",
question:  "10. The elements of Chinese vase decorations were mainly",
A: "zoomorphic",
B: "botanical.",
C: "horticultural.",
D: "geomorphic",
answer: "A. Frottage",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question11",
question:  "11. The Greek architectural styles include the Doric, Ionic and the",
A: "Pyrami",
B: "Corinthian.",
C: "Obelisk",
D: "Parthenon.",
answer: "B. Humanism.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question12",
question:  "12. Which of the following applies to a craftsman?",
A: "Hopeful and self-discipline",
B: "Ability to copy",
C: "Readiness to explore",
D: "Acceptance of new challenges",
answer: "B. Dots",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question13",
question:  "13. The colours red-violet and violet are",
A: "secondary",
B: "complementary,",
C: "analogous.",
D: "tertiary.",
answer: "C. Lyric",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question14",
question:  "14. Which of the following options is a major characteristic of the Geometric period?",
A: "Undulating rhythm",
B: "Sharply angular patterns",
C: "Circle and arc design",
D: "Vase painting",
answer: "B. Left unblocked.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question15",
question:  "15. Which of the following is a reason for studying art history?",
A: "It gives insight into the creative expression of the past.",
B: "It is one way of exploring human evolution.",
C: "It provides insight into the development of archaeology.",
D: "it sharpens our skills in art.",
answer: "A. a Spanish",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question16",
question:  "16. Soap stone sculptures are identified with the",
A: "Mossi.",
B: "Bambar",
C: "Mende.",
D: "Baule",
answer: "D. Sketch drawing",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question17",
question:  "17. The best way to promote the sale of artefacts is to",
A: "ensure good finishing of products.",
B: "retain cultural identity",
C: "place emphasis on exhibitions.",
D: "develop advertising skills.",
answer: "B. Engraving",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question18",
question:  "18. The three essential elements that make a good composition are",
A: "colour, balance, depth.",
B: "line, shape, colour.",
C: "tone, balance, depth.",
D: "line, proportion, shape.",
answer: "A. Rose period",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question19",
question:  "19. The Kingdom of Benin was famous for",
A: "metal vessel casting.",
B: "cireperdue sculptures.",
C: "goldsmithing.",
D: "bead making",
answer: "C. Gabardine",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question20",
question:  "20. The result of Renaissance art was the development of",
A: "symbolism.",
B: "conservatism.",
C: "individualism.",
D: "communism.",
answer: "C. Descriptive drawing",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question21",
question:  "21. The ideas, beliefs and practices of a society are classified as",
A: "social activity",
B: "civic education.",
C: "cultural heritage.",
D: "national identity.",
answer: "A. Libation, drumming and offering",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question22",
question:  "22. To show perspective in a painting, colours near the horizon are",
A: "pale.",
B: "intense.",
C: "bright.",
D: "warm.",
answer: "C. Everlasting life in the hereafter",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question23",
question:  "23. In the creation process, the resting period to ponder over difficulties is the",
A: "evaluation period",
B: "period of meditation.",
C: "incubation period",
D: "period of preparation.",
answer: "A. Geometric ornament and calligraphy",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question24",
question:  "24. A creative person is",
A: "self-discipline",
B: "disregards challenges",
C: "highly temperamental.",
D: "self-centred",
answer: "A. A psychological value",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question25",
question:  "25. *******************************",
A: "*******************************",
B: "*******************************",
C: "*******************************",
D: "*******************************",
answer: "B. Style",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question26",
question:  "26. In polynesia, body painting and tattooing were common among the",
A: "Asmats of New Guinea",
B: "Olmecs of Mexico.",
C: "Mayans of America",
D: "Maoris of New Zealand",
answer: "A. Egyptian and Greek letters",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question27",
question:  "27. Colour harmony is best achieved when one uses",
A: "one colour in contrast to another.",
B: "colours with different shades",
C: "different values of one colour.",
D: "colours which are not in succession on the wheel",
answer: "C. Sculpture",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question28",
question:  "28. The basic identity of a colour is",
A: "pigment.",
B: "value.",
C: "chroma",
D: "hue.",
answer: "B. Vases and panels",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question29",
question:  "29. Chemicals that are commonly used to fix dyes are",
A: "alum and caustic sod",
B: "hydrosulphite and alum.",
C: "camphor and sodium chlorid",
D: "sodium chloride and alum.",
answer: "C. Commissions works of art",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question30",
question:  "30. Full awareness of all the qualities in art is termed as",
A: "criticism.",
B: "judgment",
C: "appreciation.",
D: "creativity.",
answer: "B. Red",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question31",
question:  "31. Identify the main art form of the Neolithic period",
A: "Cave painting",
B: "Reliefs in clay",
C: "Metal implements",
D: "Sculpture-in-the round",
answer: "A. Abstraction",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question32",
question:  "32. Who among the following was the master of the High Renaissance period?",
A: "Raphael",
B: "Leonardo",
C: "Titan",
D: "Masaccio",
answer: "C. Egypt",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question33",
question:  "33. The technique of blending tones to achieve hazy effect is termed",
A: "polychrome.",
B: "sfumato.",
C: "monochrome.",
D: "chromatic",
answer: "B. Oil colour",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question34",
question:  "34. Which of the following options best describes the Mastaba?",
A: "A stone coffin surrounded by grave gods.",
B: "A small sealed chamber for housing the statue of the dead",
C: "A chapel designed to receive offerings for the dead",
D: "A flat top building above a burial chamber.",
answer: "D. Tanning",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question35",
question:  "35. Body art comprises tattoo, scarification and",
A: "coiffure.",
B: "poetr",
C: "dram",
D: "dirge.",
answer: "A. Chinese",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question36",
question:  "36. In the Nok culture, the people practiced",
A: "snake cult.",
B: "twin cult.",
C: "sympathetic magic",
D: "white magic",
answer: "C. Quietness",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question37",
question:  "37. In traditional societies, ancestors are called to help through",
A: "magic",
B: "witchcraft.",
C: "initiation.",
D: "libation.",
answer: "C. Printing",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question38",
question:  "38. Praise names bestowed on chiefs are known as",
A: "dirges.",
B: "lampoons",
C: "appellations.",
D: "proverbs.",
answer: "C. Neutral colour",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question39",
question:  "39. Hieroglyphics are referred to as the writing of priests because they were",
A: "restricted to the priesthood",
B: "written by the Egyptians.",
C: "used by the priest in healing.",
D: "found on the walls of temples.",
answer: "C. Mats",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question40",
question:  "40. Cutting out of the unwanted margin of a picture on the computer is called",
A: "skewing.",
B: "rotating.",
C: "Sizing",
D: "cropping",
answer: "C. Shais",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},


]